#### **RESUME OBJECTIVE**

Front end developer with 6+ years experience working with React/Redux and HTML/CSS/JS developing and maintaining web applications across an array of industries. Self-taught programmer that strives for innovation and continued education. Proven ability to produce quality code, optimize overall flow and improve UI experience.

# **EXPERIENCE**

July 2024 - Present | NoPlex, Philadelphia, PA

# **Consulting Front-End Engineer**

- Developed new features for task management web app using React and ios/android version using React Native
- Increased userbase through feature optimization and improvement

Nov 2022 - July 2024 | Self, Philadelphia, PA

### Freelance UI Developer

- Made a website for students of Jefferson University to enroll and pay for radiology classes. Built using Wix and custom JS components
- Made a dog info app helping users to learn more about various breeds, using React, Zustand, and ChartJS

October 2021 - October 2022 | Shift4, Allentown, PA

#### **Software Engineer III**

- Maintained and developed front end code for POS application used in secure bulk purchase transactions (e.g. Theme parks, Hotels, Stadiums)
- Developed contemporary layouts for devices including tablets and phones

July 2019 – October 2021 | Cadent, Philadelphia, PA

#### **Associate Front-End Engineer**

- Built shared React components for ad time purchasing app using React/Redux and ensured code functionality with Jest
- Fixed bugs from existing codebases and implemented enhancements to improve speed and functionality

December 2017 - September 2018 | Project One, Philadelphia, PA

#### **Junior Front-End Developer**

- Led the front-end development of an innovative web app for college students to learn and practice calculus
- Built a fully functioning MVP for higher education from the ground up

**L** 856 304 8167

Danieln.Faro@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/daniel-faro-4a4024101/

Philadelphia, PA

https://www.DanFaro.com

## **EDUCATION**

2011 Lehigh University, Bethlehem, PA

## M.S. Environmental Engineering

2010 Lehigh University, Bethlehem, PA

## **B.S. Chemical Engineering**

### **SKILLS**

React / Vue.js

HTML / CSS / IS

TypeScript

LESS/SASS

Redux / Zustand

Redux-Saga / Axios

MaterialUI / styled-components

Firebase / MongoDB / Postgres

GraphQL / SQL / Apollo

Node.js / Express

Jest / RTL / Playwright

React Native

Python